Guide to the Elizabeth Robins Papers 1803-1963 MSS 002
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Diaries
  - Subseries A: Diaries
    This subseries consists of Robins's diaries from the time she was fourteen years old (1876) to the last year of her life (1952). This subseries is remarkably complete with the exception of the 1890's.
    Robins did not always write lengthy diary entries, but she wrote often, which allows one to piece together many of her activities over the years. Sometimes she would skip days of writing in her diaries, then compensate for those periods by filling in the blank pages from memory.
    - 1876, January-March; 1880, December-1881, January, 1876 - 1881 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1880, May-August (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1880, August and September (Box 1, Folder 3)
      General note
      "Summit Rocky Mountains"
    - 1881, January, February and August-December (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1882 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1883; 1884; 1885, 1883 - 1885 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1886 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1887 (Box 2A, Folder 8)
    - 1888, January-May (Box 2A, Folder 9)
    - 1888, June-September (Box 2A, Folder 10)
    - 1888, August (Box 2A, Folder 11)
      Norwegian trip
    - 1888, September-1889, January, 1888 -1889 (Box 2A, Folder 12)
    - 1889-1894 (Box 2B, Folder 13)
      Occasional entries. Includes notes about "Katherine Fleets," an unfinished novel.
    - 1889, Janurary-May (Box 2B, Folder 14)
    - 1889, June-October (Box 2B, Folder 15)
    - 1889, September (Box 2B, Folder 16)
    - 1890, January-June (Box 2B, Folder 17)
    - 1890, July-December (Box 2B, Folder 18)
    - 1891 (Box 2B, Folder 18A)
      Notes and calendar.
    - 1892, February 20 (Box 2A, Folder 19)
      Diary pages
    - 1894 (Box 2A, Folder 19A)
    - 1894, December-1896, 1894 -1896 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - 1894-1914 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Yearly entries.
    - 1899 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Switzerland trip.
    - 1900, April-November and 1901, February, 1900 -1901 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - 1900, June (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - 1901-1902, June (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - 1904-1908, 1926, 1904 -1926 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      Occasional entries.
    - 1905, December-1906, February, 1905 -1906 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      Chinsegut Diary.
    - 1907, September-December (Box 6)
    - 1908, February, April-December (Box 6)
    - 1909-1910 (Box 6)
      Some materials removed, see Box 13, Folder 1.
    - 1911 (Box 6)
    - 1912 (Box 6)
    - 1913 (Box 6)
    - 1914 (Box 6)
    - 1915 (Box 6)
    - 1916 (Box 6)
    - 1917 (Box 6)
    - 1918 (Box 6)
    - 1919 (Box 7)
    - 1920 (Box 7)
    - 1921 (Box 7)
    - 1922 (Box 7)
    - 1923 (Box 7)
    - 1924, January, February, May-December (Box 7)
    - 1925 (Box 7)
    - 1926 (Box 7)
    - 1927 (Box 7)
    - 1928 (Box 7)
    - 1929 (Box 7)
    - 1920 (Box 7)
    - 1931 (Box 7)
    - 1932 (Box 8)
    - 1933 (Box 8)
    - 1934 (Box 8)
    - 1935 (Box 8)
    - 1936 (Box 8)
    - 1937 (Box 8)
    - 1938 (Box 8)
    - 1939 (Box 8)
    - 1940, January-March, June-July (Box 8)
    - 1940, August-October (Box 8)
    - 1940, October-1941, February, 1940 -1941 (Box 8)
    - 1941, February-December (Box 8)
    - 1942, March-July (Box 8)
    - 1943 (Box 9)
    - 1944 (Box 9)
    - 1945 (Box 9)
    - 1947 (Box 9)
    - 1948 (Box 9)
    - 1949 (Box 9)
    - 1951 (Box 9)
    - 1952 (Box 9)
  - Subseries B: Engagement Books
    While some of the engagement books in this subseries are nearly blank, others contain pages full of her notes and are helpful to use in conjunction with the diaries.
    - Address Books (Box 9)
      3 volumes.
    - Theatrical Diary, 1885-1886 (Box 9)
    - 1892-1912, 1916-1920, 1922-1925, 1891 -1925 (Box 10)
      30 volumes.
  - Subseries C: Notebooks
    Subseries C contains notebooks dating back to 1873, when Robins was eleven years old. There are composition books from her time at the Putnam Female Seminary in Ohio, as well as records of books she read and a drawing book from 1879-1880. Also in this series are thirty-three volumes of small notebooks ranging in date from 1877-1940.
    - Compositions, 1873-1874 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Legal size materials removed, see Box 13, Folder 13.
    - Composition Book, 1874 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Composition Book, 1875 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Composition Book, 1881 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - School Copy Book, 0000 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Putnam Seminary.
    - Drawing Book, 1879-1880 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - List of Books Read, 1879-1880; Family Genealogy (Box 11, Folder 7)
      See back of book for genealogy.
    - List of Books Read, 1881-1882 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - "Odds and Ends", 1880 -1881? (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Notebook, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Notebook, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Small Notebooks, 1877-1940 (Box 12)
      35 volumes.
    - Composition Book, 1873-1874, n.d (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - List of Books Read, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Materials Removed from Diaries, 1911-1951 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Statement about the accuracy of Elizabeth Robins' account of herself, 16 March 1895 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "To G.R.P.", 1912 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      G.R.P. is George Richmond Parks.
- Series II: General Correspondence
  The General Correspondence series is composed primarily of letters written to Elizabeth Robins. Copies of, or notes on, her outgoing correspondence are filed chronologically under the name of the person addressed.
  - Subseries A: General Correspondence, 1873-1887
    Subseries A contains letters from childhood friends, relatives, family friends, actors, actresses and admirers. There are also letters from Dr. Andrew McLaughlin of the Oak Lawn Retreat for the Insane in Jacksonville, Illinois where Robins's mother, Hannah Crow Robins, was committed for several years.
    Robins and her husband, George Richmond Parks, traveled separately in their work, and many letters from Parks to Robins survive. The letters begin during their courtship in 1884 and end with Parks's suicide note in 1887. Folder 47 contains Parks's record book in which he recorded his theatrical engagements (date, place, play, part) for the years 1877-1886. Folder 44 includes newspaper clippings about his suicide.
    Elizabeth Robins moved to England in May of 1888 and created an entirely new life for herself. She continued to correspond with her family but lost contact with most of her friends and acquaintances from her early years. The letters of the few American friends and relatives who continued to write after 1887, including Lloyd Tevis, president of Wells Fargo and a maternal cousin of Robins's, who sponsored her early acting career, can be found in Subseries B. Some letters to and from childhood friends can be found in two letterbooks, which date from 1878-1881. The majority of these refer to Robins's four-month stay in the Rocky Mountains during her eighteenth summer. [See also Series Three: Robins Family Papers.]
    - "A" 1878-1887 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Andariese, A.M. 1881-1887, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      See also Subseries B, Box 6, Folders 1 and 2: "A".
    - "B" 1881-1887, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Backus, George 1882-1884, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Barrett, Lawrence n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Blandy, Emma 1876-1887 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Blandy: Emma, Julia n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bodine: J.M., M.E., Elizabeth 1883-1887 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      See also Subseries B, Box 10, Folder 31: "Bodine"; Subseries B, Box 19, Folder 132: "McKay, Elizabeth Bodine"; and Oversize Materials, Box 1, Folder 1.
    - Buckingham, Ellen (Nellie) 1874-1877, n.d., 1874 -1878 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bull, Sara Thorp (Mrs. Ole Bull) 1886-1887 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      See also Subseries B, Box 10, Folder 34.
    - Bullitt: Anne, Edith, Sallie 1873-1877, 1884-1889, n.d., 1873 -1887 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "C" 1881-1887 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Cordes, Albert 1883-1887 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      See also Subseries B, Box 10, Folders 37 and 38: "C".
    - Cutter, Nina 1884-1887 (Mrs. Hollis B. Page) (Box 2, Folder 14)
      See also Subseries B, Box 10, Folders 37 and 38: "C"
    - Culbertson, Annie V. 1883-1887, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "D" 1880-1885, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - "E" 1883-1887, 1880 -1887 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - "F" 1880-1887 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Field, R.M. 1883-1884, 1887, 1883 -1887 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Boston Museum Company
    - Fulton: S.H., Mary 1883-1887 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - "G" 1882-1887 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Galvin: Charlotte, Carroll, Mary, Edward 1883-1887 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Granger, Moses, M. 1882-1887 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      See also Series Three: Robins Family Papers and Subseries B, Box 13, Folder 74: "Granger and Granger."
    - "H" 1874-1887, n.d (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Hedley: Mary B., Anne 1881-1887, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Jordan, Louise 1885-1886, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      See also Subseries B, Box 25, Folder 187.
    - Kealhofer, Isabel (Mrs. R.H. Kealhofer) 1882-1884, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Kent, Millie 1887 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Keyser, Francis 17 May 1885 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - LeGree, Grace 1883-1884 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Lincoln, Kate 3 June 1882 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Longstreet, A.B. 1883-1887, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "M" 1882-1885, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Mack: Rebecca, Charles, Howard, Grace 1880-1887, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - McFarland, Dr. Andrew 1886-1887 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - McLaughlin, Elizabeth H. 1883-1885, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - "N" 1884, 1886, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - "O" 1883-1887, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - "P" 1881-1887, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Parks, George Richmond May-December 1883, July 1884, 1883 -1884 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      See also Subseries B, Box 19, Folder 139: "P," letter dated 19 July 1892.
    - Parks, George Richmond January-October 1885 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Parks, George Richmond November-December 1885 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Parks, George Richmond February-October 1886 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Parks, George Richmond January-May 1887 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Parks, George Richmond n.d. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Parks, George Richmond n.d. (Box 3, Folder 46)
      Boston Museum Scripts
    - Parks, George Richmond: programs 1879-1885, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 46A)
    - Parks, George Richmond Record Book 1877-1886 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Parks: Emily, Helen, Randall, John 1885-1887 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Parmele: Alfred, Annie 1881-1887, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Parsons, Hosmer B. 1882-1887 (Box 4, Folder 50)
      See also Folder 56: "Tevis, Lloyd."
    - Potwin: Kate, Sarah 1880-1885, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 51)
      See also Subseries B, Box 19, Folder 139: "P."
    - "R" 1881-1887 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Raven, Grace ("Nita Sin") 1886-1887 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      See also Subseries B, Box 20, Folder 148: "R."
    - "S" 1877-1887 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - "T" 1875-1887 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Tevis, Lloyd 1882-1887 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Vinton, Blanche 26 January 1884 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Von Sachs, Julius 1883-1886, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - "W" 1881-1886 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Ward, Ada Weber 1881-1886, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Letterpress Book 1880-1881 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Letterbook 1878-1880 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Subseries B: General Correspondence, 1888-1952
    Subseries B includes the bulk of Elizabeth Robins's correspondence and reflects her activities -- acting, managing, writing, women's suffrage, and personal relationships -- for the remainder of her life. However, Robin’s correspondence with Florence Bell can be found in Series V: Florence Bell; with Octavia Wilberforce, Subseries C, Box 29, Folders 4 and 5: "Backsettown" and Series VI: Octavia Wilberforce; and with her brother Raymond and his wife Margaret, Series IV: Raymond Robins and Margaret Dreier Robins.
    - "A" 1888-1913 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "A" 1915-1942, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Achurch, Janet 1895, 1896, 1902, 1895 -1902 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Ailen, Grant 1895, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 3a)
    - Ameen, Elin 1893-1896, 1902, 1893 -1902 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Archdale, Helen Alexander 1920-1921, 1926, 1920 -1926 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Secretary, Time and Tide
    - Archer, Charles 1923-1940 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Archer, William 1891, 1890 (Box 7a, Folder 7.1)
      See also Folder 18 "B," n.d.
    - Archer, William May-December 1891 (Box 7a, Folder 7.2)
    - Archer, William 1892-1897 (Box 7a, Folder 8)
    - Archer, William 1900-1924 (Box 7a, Folder 9)
    - Archer, William [undated] (Box 7a, Folder 10)
    - Archer, William [Correspondence to/from] 1891-1914, [undated] (Box 7a, Folder 11)
    - Archer, William [Criticisms], [undated] (Box 7b, Folder 12)
    - Archer, William [Newspaper contributions], [undated] (Box 7b, Folder 13)
    - Archer, William [Plot abstracts], [undated] (Box 7b, Folder 14)
    - Archer, William [Writings], [undated] (Box 7b, Folder 15)
    - Archer, William [Verses], [undated] (Box 7b, Folder 16)
    - ["B"] 1888-1948 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - ["B", undated] (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Barker, Harley Granville 1898-1914, 1918-1920, 1928, n.d., 1898 -1928 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      See also Series VII, Box 18, Folder 15.
    - Barrie, Sir James M. 1891-1907, 1919, 1936, 1891 -1936 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Beecher, Henry Ward n.d. (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Bell, Gertrude 1893-1926, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 22)
      See also Series VII: Additional Titles - "Bell, Gertrude."
    - Bell, Hugh 1893-1902 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Bell, Hugh 1909-1910 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Bell, Hugh 1913-1919 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Bell, Hugh 1920-1927 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Bell, Hugh 1928-1931, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Bell, Hugh: Correspondence to/from 1892-1893, 1914, 1924, 1892 -1924 (Box 9, Folder 28)
      See Oversize Material, Box 1, Folder 3 for Gertrude Bell to HB.
    - Bell: Maurice, Hugo, Frances, Lowthian 1893, 1923, 1930, 1931, n.d., 1893 -1931 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Blandy, Emma (Mrs. R.H. Carrington) 1891-1939, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 30)
      Two letters from Julia Blandy; see also Subseries A, Box 1, Folders 5 and 6.
    - Bodine: Dr. James Morrison, Mary 1893, 1898, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 31)
      See also Subseries A, Box 1, Folder 8.
    - Booth, Edwin 4 June 1888 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      See also "Tevis, Lloyd," n.d.
    - Brown, Harrison 1928 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Bull, Sara Thorp (Mrs. Ole Bull) 1888, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 34)
      See also Subseries A, Box 1, Folder 10.
    - Buxton: Charles, Denis, Doreen, Phyllis 1910-1921 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Buxton, Mildred 1908-1939, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - "C" 1888-1919 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - "C" 1920-1949, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Campbell, Beatrice Stella (Mrs. Patrick Campbell) 1893, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Carr, Comyns 1897, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Catt, Carrie Chapman 8 February 1908 (Box 10, Folder 41)
      President, International Woman Suffrage Alliance.
    - Clemens, Samuel L. (Mark Twain) 1899, 1904 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Clifford, Lucy 1894-1929, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Crackenthorpe, B.A. 1892-1906, 1914, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Crane, Cora (Mrs. Stephen Crane) 8 May 1899 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Crawfurd, Oswald 1889-1895 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Crowe, Kate 1893-1897 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - "D" 1888-1942 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Dabbs, Dr. G. 1889-1890, 1904, 1889 -1904 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Davy, B.H. (Honour) 1937-1947, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Dreier: Katherine, Theodore 1905-1931, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Dreier, Mary 1911-1950, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - DuBois, W.E.B. 1908 (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Duckworth, Gerald 1896-1931, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - "E" 1889-1940, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Earl, Alfred 1923-1938, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 56)
      See also Series VII: Additional Titles - "Letters to the Editor."
    - Edel, Leon 1932-1950 (Box 12, Folder 57)
    - Eliot: Elsa, Henrietta, Sam 1906-1952 (Box 12, Folder 58)
    - Eliot, T.S. 23 May 1918 (Box 12, Folder 59)
    - Evans, C.S. 1931-1940, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 60)
    - "F" 1890-1944, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 61)
    - Fellows, Evelyn 1932-1950, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 62)
      See also Subseries C, Box 29, Folders 4 and 5: "Backsettown," August 1930.
    - Fletcher, Constance 1893-1902, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 63)
    - Forbes-Robertson: J., Gertrude, Ian 1891-1933, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 64)
    - Fulton: S.H., Margaret, L.B., Mary 1888-1913 (Box 12, Folder 65)
      See also Subseries A, Box 2, Folder 20.
    - "G" 1888-1939 (Box 12, Folder 66)
    - Galsworthy: John, Ada 1918-1919, 1930, 1918 -1930 (Box 12, Folder 67)
    - Galvin, Mary E. 1888-1890 (Box 12, Folder 68)
    - Gardner: Karolina, Elizabeth, Raimond, Leopold 1901, 1908-1933, n.d., 1901 -1933 (Box 12, Folder 69)
      See also Box 24, Folders 173 and 174: "Simmonds, Florence," 1913; Oversize Material, Box 1, Folder 4.
    - Gaskell, May 1925-1932 (Box 13, Folder 70)
    - Gaskell: M.E., Julia 1894, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 71)
    - Gosse: Edmund, Nellie 1891-1894, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 72)
    - Graham: R.G., James, Harriet 1893-1899, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 73)
    - Granger and Granger, Attorneys at Law 1888, 1900, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 74)
      See also Subseries A, Box 2, Folder 23.
    - Green, Alice Stopford (Mrs. J.R. Green) 1892-1928, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 75)
      See also Series V, Subseries A, Box 1, Folder 2: ER to FB, 17 July 1893 and Summer 1893 letters from Wimbledon.
    - Grein, J.T. 1891-1896 (Box 13, Folder 76)
    - Grey: Sir Edward, Lady Dorothy 1898-1906, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 77)
      See also Series VII: Additional Titles - "Grey"
    - Grey: Sir Edward, Lady Dorothy 1907-1937, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 78)
    - Greig, Edvard 3 February 1896 (Box 13, Folder 79)
    - Grosvenor, Caroline 1896-1938, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 80)
      See also Susie and Alys Buchau in Box 8, Folders 17 and 18.
    - Guiney, Louise Imogen, 1890 -1891 (Box 13, Folder 81)
    - "H" 1889-1919 (Box 14, Folder 82)
    - "H" 1921-1950 (Box 14, Folder 83)
    - "H" n.d. (Box 14, Folder 84)
    - Hadwen, Zoe (Margaret) 1908-1917 (Box 15, Folder 85)
    - Hadwen, Zoe (Margaret) 1918-1941, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 86)
    - Hamilton, Cicely 1912-1914, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 87)
      See also Series VII, Box 75, Folder 16.
    - Hamilton: Lady Jean, Sir Ian 1907-1940, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 88)
    - Hamilton, Mary Agnes (Molly) 1907, 1921-1931, 1907 -1931 (Box 16, Folder 89)
    - Hardy, Thomas 1896,1919, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 90)
      See also Box 11, Folder 44: "Crackenthorpe, B.A.," 7 June 1896.
    - Harraden, Beatrice 1911-1930, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 91)
    - Hehir, M. 1917-1918 (Box 16, Folder 92)
    - Heinemann: William, Magda 1891-1913, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 93)
      Including some letters to W.H.
    - Herford, C.H. 1893, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 94)
      Including ER and William Archer notes on Ibsen.
    - Hoover, Herbert 9 January 1933 (Box 16, Folder 95)
    - House, Colonel Edward M. 1916, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 96)
    - Hubert, Dr. Marjorie Browning 1924-1950, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 97)
      See also Subseries C, Box 29, Folders 4 and 5: "Backsettown."
    - Hughes, Charles 1894 (Box 16, Folder 98)
    - "I" 1893-1938, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 99)
    - Ibsen, Henrik 7 August 1893 (Box 16, Folder 100)
      See also Box 7, Folder 8 for correspondence to William Archer, 30 June 1893.
    - Irving, Henry 1894-1914, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 101)
    - Irving, Laurence 1907, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 102)
    - "J" 1889-1941, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 103)
    - James, Henry 1891, 1905-1906, n.d., 1891 -1906 (Box 17, Folder 104)
      See also Series VII, Box 61, Folders 7-10.
    - James: Henry, Dorothea (nephew of Henry James )1930-1947, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 105)
    - Jenny-Streiff, Marie 1938-1939 (Box 17, Folder 106)
    - Jenny-Streiff, Marie 1940-1944, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 107)
      See also Box 24, Folder 175: "Simons, Hans."
    - "K" 1888-1946, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 108)
    - Kenney, Annie 1907, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 109)
      Women's Suffrage and Political Union.
    - Kingston, Gertrude 1906,1914, n.d. (Mrs. Gertrude Silver) (Box 17, Folder 110)
    - Kohler, C. (?Katrine)ca. 1895-1896 (Box 17, Folder 111)
    - "L" 1890-1941, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 112)
    - Laughton, Vera S. (Elvira Sibyl Laughton) 1920 (Box 17, Folder 113)
      Journalist, Time and Tide; see also Subseries C,Box 29, Folder 12.
    - Lawler, Geraldine 1929-1933,1949, n.d., 1929 -1949 (Box 18, Folder 114)
    - Lea, Marion (Mrs. Langdon Mitchell) 1891-1932, n.d (Box 18, Folder 115)
    - Levinson, Salmon O. 1936-1937 (Box 18, Folder 116)
      See also Series IV: Raymond Robins and Margaret Dreier Robins.
    - Lewis: Lady Betty, Katie 1899-1933, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 117)
    - Low, Frances H. 1909 (Box 18, Folder 118)
    - Lowndes, Marie Belloc 1913, 1932-1940, n.d., 1913 -1940 (Box 18, Folder 119)
      See also Series VII, Box 62, Folder 16.
    - "M" 1891-1929 (Box 18, Folder 120)
    - "M" 1930-1950, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 121)
    - MacDonald, J. Ramsay 1933 (Box 19, Folder 122)
    - Mack: Rebecca Robins, Laura Test, Julian, Cornelia, Mrs. S.E. 1888, 1939-1952, 1888 -1952 (Box 19, Folder 123)
    - Macnamara, Margaret 1911, 1918-1934, n.d., 1911 -1934 (Box 19, Folder 124)
      Henfield Women's Institute.
    - Macready, William, 0000 (Box 19, Folder *)
      See Box 20, Folder 145: Pollock, 3 letters from 1860s.
    - Maeterlinck, M. 1895 (Box 19, Folder 125)
    - Marbury, Elisabeth 1898-1932, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 126)
      See also Series VII: Literary Productions.
    - Martindale, Dr. L. 1913-1947 (Box 19, Folder 127)
      See also Subseries C, Box 29, Folder 13: "USA Trip."
    - Martyn, Edward 1900 (Box 19, Folder 128)
    - Masefield: John, Constance 1918, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 129)
      See also Box 10, Folder 38: "C," 7 December 1939.
    - Maugham, W. Somerset n.d. (Box 19, Folder 139)
    - McClure, Grace (Mrs. C.F.W. McClure) 1943-1945, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 131)
    - McKay, Elizabeth Bodine 1913-1934 (Box 19, Folder 132)
      See also Subseries A.
    - Milne, Louise Jordan 1892,1895-1896, 1892 -1896 (Box 19, Folder 133)
      See also Subseries A, Box 2, Folder 26: Jordan, Louise."
    - Moore, George 1893, 1896, 1932, n.d., 1893 -1932 (Box 19, Folder 134)
      See also Box 7, Folder 11: "Archer, William."
    - "N" 1891-1949, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 135)
    - Nevinson, Henry Woodd 1915-1934, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 136)
    - "M.D.N." 1945 (Box 19, Folder 137)
    - "O" 1893, 1907-1937, n.d., 1893 -1937 (Box 19, Folder 138)
    - "P" 1888-1951, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 139)
    - Pankhurst: Emmeline, Christabel, Sylvia 1906-1941 (Box 19, Folder 140)
    - Paul, Alice, 0000 (Box 20, Folder *)
      See Folder 142: Pethick-Lawrence, 26 February 1940.
    - Pawling, Syndey S. 1895-1920, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 141)
    - Pethick-Lawrence: Sir Frederick, Emmeline 1907, 1913, 1944, n.d., 1907 -1944 (Box 20, Folder 142)
      Includes one Alice Paul letter, 31 January 1940; see also Box 17, Folders 106 and 107: "Jenny-Streiff, Marie" and Oversize Material, Box 1, Folder 5.
    - Pinero, Sir Arthur Wing 1889-1919 (Box 20, Folder 143)
    - Poel, William 1888-1891,1932, n.d., 1888 -1932 (Box 20, Folder 144)
    - Pollock: Sir Frederick, Georgina, John, Alice 1893-1937, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 145)
      Includes 3 letters from William Macready to F.P.
    - Potwin, Kate 1935-1939 (Box 20, Folder 146)
      See also Subseries A, Box 4, Folder 51: Potwin.
    - Quilter, Harry 1890 (Box 20, Folder 147)
    - "R" 1892-1946, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 148)
    - Reynolds, Paul R. 1890, 1906-1933, 1890 -1933 (Box 20, Folder 149)
    - Rhondda, Viscountess (Margaret Haig Mackworth) 1918-1950, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 150)
      Time and Tide
    - Richmond, Lady Elsa (Bell)1893-1949, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 151)